in this problem
we're going to write an if statement
that prints the sun
is so bright if sun is equal to visible
and an unless statement that prints the
clouds are blocking the sun
unless sun equals visible
on line 3 we'll output the value of sun
just for debugging purposes as we write
out the logic in this program
so beginning with our if statement we
want
our if statement to print the sun is so
bright if sun
is equal to the string visible
secondly we need to write an unless
statement
that prints the clouds are blocking the
sun unless sun equals visible
let's run our code and see our program
in action
[Music]
when the sun is visible our program
prints the sun is so bright
and when it's hidden our program prints
the clouds are blocking the sun
so we're seeing all of the desired
behavior
however we can change our code a little
bit to be
shorter and easier to read and we can do
this using statement modifiers
instead of writing a longer if statement
that uses both
if and end
we can put all this code on one line
now this reads very naturally the sun is
so bright if sun is equal to visible
not only is this code shorter but it's
very easy to read
and let's do the same thing with our
unless statement
[Music]
let's run our code now and we can see
that it exhibits the same behavior
[Music]
this is an example of a time that we can
take advantage of
what an expressive language ruby is